(匈牙利  布达佩斯)
(火车西站)
(杀手 莫洛)
(俄罗斯  莫斯科兰卡监狱)
嗨 你怎么出来了?
Hey, how did you open your cell door?
- 嘘  - 嗨
- Shh! - Hey!
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
二区开门
Open Sector 2!
你怎么出来的?
How did you get out?
快回号子里去
Get back in your cell.
听到吗 快滚回去
I told you, get back in your cell!
我给你找几个伴儿玩玩
Let's give you a few friends to play with.
对不起
Sorry.
快叫警卫进去
Send some guards in.
联系不上
I'm trying.
我这边好了 你那边怎么样
Okay, I'm set. How's things going down below?
下水道里还能怎么样
How do you think? I'm in a sewer.
门打不开 我们被锁住了
The doors won't open! We're locked in!
拉响警报
Sound the alarm!
我们想关牢房门 可是都关不上
We've lost control!
上尉
Captain!
到底出了什么问题
怎么会这样
- 情况就要失控了  - 快想办法
我就位了
I'm in position.
开始下一步
Move to phase 2.
(迪安·马丁 《多么意想不到》)
你在干嘛？你在干嘛？
What are you doing? What are you doing?
怎么了？出了什么问题？
What's wrong? What's happening, Benji?
那家伙没去撤离点
Oh, God. He's not going to the extraction point.
别紧张  他心里有数
Stay focused. He knows where he's going.
不 我不干 我不会打开那扇门的
No, I'm not. I won't. I will not open that door.
拜托 快去撤离点 伊森
Please go to the extraction point, Ethan. I know.
我知道 我懂你的意思 可是我不能 我没有权力
I know what this means, but I can't. I'm not authorized...
快到撤离点去 伊森
Go to the extraction point, Ethan.
你赶紧去撤离点
Go to the extraction point!
噢 我不开 你就这么一直等着
Oh, you're just going to wait.
嗯 我陪你等
We're going to wait. Great. I can wait.
你们在哪里 我们需要支援 请回话
行了 我开 我开 算你狠
Okay, fine. Fine! Fine!
在那里
There.
好了 现在计划全乱了 都怪你
We'll just screw the whole thing up on purpose.
嗨 你不能过去 快回来
请赶快派人支援
简 我们的计划有点小变化
Uh, Jane? We're going to have a slight delay.
你去那儿干嘛？
Why do you want to go in there?
波格丹 波格丹
Bogdan! Bogdan!
谢尔盖
Sergei?
快走
Time to go!
现在走？
Now?
对 现在就走
Yes, now!
我连他想干嘛都不知道 居然就在帮他
I don't know what he's doing, and for some reason, I'm helping him.
歌曲结束 他能到位就行
As long as he's where he should be when the song ends.
呃 我们多了个乘客
Uh, we have a passenger.
谢尔盖
Sergei!
把门都打开
Open all of them!
那边
That way
快走
Run
天呐
Oh God!
噢 天呐 天呐 天呐
Oh God oh God oh God. ..
谢尔盖 难道这就是你的计划吗？
Sergei, please tell me there's more to this plan!
哇哦
Whoa!
快走
Let's go. ..
你是亨特？
Agent Hunt?
你是？
And you are?
我是卡特
Agent Carter.
好的
Okay.
他是谁？
Who's your pal?
路上告诉你
I'll tell you on the way!
点燃引线
Light the fuse.
《碟中谍4：幽灵协议》
谢尔盖 这是怎么回事？
Sergei, what's going on?
没事的 波格丹
It's OK, Bogdan.
其实我不想多嘴
I don't mean to bring up the elephant in the room,
可这个毛茸茸的俄国佬是干嘛的？
but what's with the big, hairy Russian?
你说波格丹吗？他是我的线人 把他留下 他会死的
Who, Bogdan? He fed me intel. If I left him there, they would've killed him.
所以我把他带出来
So we're gonna give him his freedom.
通知清扫队了吗？
Did you call in the sweepers?
已经在路上了
On their way.
很好
Good, good.
班吉 你怎么会来这儿？
Uh, Benji, how is it you're here?
我通过实战考核了
Oh, I passed the field exam.
没想到吧？
Crazy, right?
是啊 真没想到
Yeah. Crazy.
- DNA测试  - 是我
- DNA test.  - It's me.
只是例行程序 确认一下
It's procedure. I'm just confirming it's you.
- 用得着吗？  - 谢尔盖
- You're very thorough. - Sergei?
你不是俄罗斯人？
Are you not Russian?
别紧张
Relax.
清扫队来了 扫帚准备好了
Sweepers approaching! Brooms are out!
- 收到  - 谢尔盖
- Roger that. - Sergei.
你也不叫谢尔盖？
Are you not Sergei?
没事的
You'll be fine.
波格丹
Bogdan.
我一向很照顾朋友
I always take care of my friends.
我的朋友
My friend.
他肯定一头雾水
Messy bringing him along.
计划很顺利
I thought it went rather well.
为什么你会在俄罗斯监狱里？
Mind telling me what you were doing in a Russian prison?
为什么要帮我越狱？
Mind telling me why you broke me out?
这不是营救任务吗？
This wasn't a rescue mission?
这么说吧
Uh, let me put it this way.
部长把我从牢里弄出来
If the Secretary wanted me out of there,
说明外面有大麻烦
it must be pretty bad out here.
我们在找一份文件
We were after a file.
我们弄丢了
We lost it.
"我们"？谁弄丢的？你吗？
"We"? Who lost it? You?
哈纳韦特工
Agent Hanaway.
他在哪儿？
Where's Hanaway?
他去截获一份文件
It was a letter drop.
绝密文件
Classified file.
很简单的拦截任务
It should have been a simple intercept.
我们知道情报员坐哪班车
We knew which train the courier was on.
呃 情报员两分钟后到达
Uh, ETA, two minutes on the courier.
可有一件事我们不知道
But there was one thing we didn't know.
山猫 你的车已出站六分钟
Bobcat, your train's six minutes out.
不知道情报员是谁
Who the courier was.
快行动 山猫
It's now or never, Bobcat.
拿文件的情报员 他叫什么名字？
The courier delivering the file, what's his name?
动手吧 开枪啊
Go ahead. Shoot.
我们没时间了
We are out of time.
快把名字告诉我 我不可能跟踪这么多人
I need a name, folks. I can't track all these people at once.
马克·斯特凡斯基 看在上帝的份上
Marek. Stefanski. For the love of God!
听到吗？
You got it?
马克·斯特凡斯基
Marek Stefanski.
搜索
Searching.
(锁定)
我来搞定
I'll take it from here.
哇 哇
Ow! Ow!
嗨 没事吧 老兄？
Hey, you all right, buddy?
哈纳韦弄晕马克 拿走了包
Hanaway dropped the mark and grabbed his bag.
歇一会儿 喘口气
Sit down. Catch your breath.
哈纳韦拿到了文件 准备撤离
He had the file in his hands. Easy in, easy out.
文件到手了
File secured.
可要这文件的不止我们
But we weren't the only ones after it.
山猫 看来有人不请自来
Bobcat, someone else has crashed this party.
我被跟踪了
I'm not alone.
当地警察？
Local police?
不 是敌人
No. Armed hostiles.
坚持住 我来了 桨栓 支援他
Hang tight, I'm coming! Outrigger, back him up.
不用 桨栓
Negative, Outrigger.
一分钟后在西南角碰头
Rendezvous southwest corner, 60 seconds.
哈纳韦的摄像头做了面部比对 发出警报
Hanaway's lens cam drew a facial match and triggered a warning.
可太晚了
But it was too late.
不
No!
你会没事的
You're going to be okay.
你真美
You're so beautiful.
对不起 我该早点告诉你
I'm sorry, I. .. I should have told you.
是我指挥的任务
It was my op.
是我派他去的
I put him in the field.
杀手故意给他留了口气 让我看着他死
And she left him just alive enough for me to see him die.
对不起
I'm sorry.
认识吗？
You know her?
萨宾·莫洛 职业杀手
That's Sabine Moreau. Contract killer.
只收钻石
Works for diamonds.
那是什么文件？
What was in the file?
俄罗斯的核弹发射密码
Russian nuclear launch codes.
IMF一直在找一个极端分子 代号克伯特
IMF's been looking for an emerging extremist, code name, Cobalt.
这个人想尽一切办法要引爆核弹
He's determined to detonate a nuclear weapon however he can.
莫洛以前替他干过活
We know Moreau's worked for him before.
IMF还知道什么？
What else does IMF know about him?
就知道这些
As much as you do now.
如果莫洛拿到了核弹发射密码
But if Moreau has nuclear launch codes,
那不用猜 这个克伯特绝对是幕后黑手
you can bet Cobalt's gone from a person of interest to enemy number one.
我们到了
We're here.
特工确认
Agent confirmed.
他为什么会坐牢？
Why was he in prison?
他跟老婆离婚之后失踪了
He disappeared after he and his wife... You know.
我以为他被调走了 停薪留职
I thought he'd just been transferred. Put on leave.
也有传言说 他未经批准杀人
There were rumors, though. Talk of an unsanctioned hit.
欢迎回来 亨特先生
Welcome back, Mr. Hunt.
你不在的时候 IMF发现克伯特现在或者曾经是
In your absence, IMF has learned that Cobalt is or was
俄罗斯情报局的一级核战略师
a level-1 nuclear strategist for Russian intelligence.
因此要想查清他的真实身份
Therefore, the only way to uncover his actual identity
必须潜入克里姆林宫
is to infiltrate the Kremlin itself.
为了通过检查岗哨
In order to get past their checkpoints,
你将扮成安纳托利·费德洛夫将军
you'll be impersonating General Anatoly Fedorov.
我们认为克伯特会想尽一切办法
We believe Cobalt will do everything he can
销毁他的身份记录
to destroy any record of his identity.
你将决定是否接受这个任务
Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
潜入高度防卫的克里姆林宫档案室
is to penetrate the highly-secured archive inside the Kremlin...
赶在克伯特前面拿到他的身份资料
and retrieve Cobalt's file before he can destroy it.
最新情报显示克伯特已经上路了 你还有...
New intel suggests Cobalt is already en route, leaving you. ..
...4小时52分钟...
...4 hours 52 minutes...
...去执行任务
...to infiltrate.
为了节约时间 我们帮你选好了队员
To save time, we've chosen your team for you.
特工简和班吉
Agents Carter and Dunn.
老规矩 如果你或你的团队成员被抓或被杀
As always, should you or any member of your team be caught or killed,
部长将表示对你们的行动并不知情
the Secretary will disavow any knowledge of your actions.
该消息将在5秒后自动销毁
This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
祝你好运 伊森
Good luck, Ethan.
怎么说？
What do you got?
去克里姆林宫
We're going into the Kremlin.
你是开玩笑吧 真去克里姆林宫？
I thought you said "The Kremlin."
好吧
Okay.
我太激动了
This is very exciting.
能和你搭档执行任务
Being out in the field with you, you know.
这是我的梦想
It's a bit of a dream for me.
你的妆化得很棒 一模一样
Love your disguise, by the way. You look just like him.
真可惜 不用戴面具 我一直想戴戴看
It's a shame we're not wearing masks. You know, like, full masks.
你们都戴过 就我没有
Everybody gets to wear a mask but Benji.
对不起
Sorry.
我一紧张就絮絮叨叨的
I'm tense. I babble when I'm nervous.
我又来了 闭嘴 班吉
I'm doing it again. Shut up, Benji.
这里有七个保安
Okay, seven security guards.
X光机 摄像头金属探测器
X-ray machines. Cameras. Metal detectors.
和估计的一样 没问题
Just what we expected. We can do this.
准备投放 三 二 一
Releasing in three, two, one.
别紧张 别紧张 快进入状态
Game face, game face. Kremlin game face.
将军请留步
General...
我是叶戈洛夫少校
I am Major Egorov.
请出示您的证件
Your documents.
你连自己的长官都认不出来吗？
You should know your boss.
(搜索)
(拒绝访问)
资料库里没有
I can't find you.
再扫描一次...
Run it again...
二等兵...
...Private.
叶戈洛夫
Egorov.
(安纳托利·费德洛夫将军)
对不起 将军 我刚才没有认出您
Excuse me, General. I didn't recognize you.
你要倒霉了 叶戈洛夫
You're going to regret this, Egorov.
看来一切都很顺利
I think that went quite well.
快闭嘴
Just shut it.
抱歉
Sorry.
你好
是啊
对
会成功的
It's going to work.
噢 对了 我很遗憾 关于你和朱莉娅
I'm sorry, by the way. About you and Julia.
我知道你们分手了
You know, not working out.
你上次走的时候我就想跟你说的
I wanted to say something before you went away, but. ..
我喜欢她
I liked her, you know.
他挂电话了
He's off the phone now.
(渲染完成)
没东西
It's empty.
鸟窝是空的
The nest is empty.
报告位置 队长
Check in, Team Leader.
完毕
Over.
重复 报告位置 队长
Repeat. Check in, Team Leader.
你们到档案室了吗？
Have you made it to the Archive Room?
上尉 有人闯入档案室
Captain! The Archive Room!
快去
Run!
有人黑进了我们的通讯频率
Someone is piggybacking our frequency.
队长
Team Leader,
我等你的指示 随时待命 准备引爆
awaiting your go-sign. Standing by to detonate.
中止计划
Abort.
在92碰头
Rendezvous nine-two.
听着 有情况
- 见鬼 - 快追
赶快把大门关上
Shut the gate!
快点
Quickly!
官方称克里姆林宫地下的煤气总管
今天突然爆裂
引发了一系列连锁反应
目前还不清楚克里姆林宫的
哪些部门受到了影响
不过据内部知情人士透露
在克里姆林宫北部角的地面上
发现了一个巨大的弹坑
官方已向公众做出保证
泄漏的煤气不会造成危害
我们的媒体和你们的一样不可信
Our media is no more truthful than yours,
美国佬
American.
我们都知道 引发这起大爆炸的人...
But we both know that the real cause of the explosion...
就是你
was you.
队长 我等你的指示
Awaiting your go-sign, Team Leader.
随时待命 准备引爆
Standing by to detonate.
碰上我 算你倒霉
The worst part for you,
我的队长
"Team Leader,"
我从不手下留情 你破坏我的国家
is I am the man assigned to make you suffer for it.
我要你付出代价
For what you did to my country.
这儿是医院...
This is a hospital. ..
不是酒吧 走开
Not a night club.Go.
米莎 来帮忙
Misha. ..help me here...
12号房
Room twelve.
听医生说 这家伙能活下来 算他命大
The doctors say he's lucky to be alive.
只是有点轻微的脑震荡
Only a mild concussion.
他的健康关我屁事
I don't give a damn about his health.
他是重要嫌疑犯 我们要带他回去问话
I have questions that need answering.
走路看着点儿
Be careful!
准备车辆
Prepare a transport.
看看那边
Check over there!
跳下去可不明智
Not a good idea.
你说的有道理
It seemed like one a minute ago.
嗨 你找死啊
见鬼 该死的家伙
全体注意 目标正在朝西边跑了
All agents! Hot target heading west!
统一保险
Consolidated Insurance.
要帮忙吗？
How may I help you?
萨特20 特工82DE 请求立即撤离
SAT 20. Agent 82-Delta-Echo requesting immediate evac.
团队会合地点 A113
Rendezvous Alpha 113.
确认 A113
Confirmed. Alpha 113.
今天由于克里姆林宫
地下的煤气总管突然爆裂
造成多人受伤
原因可能是煤气管道老化
在广场的下方布满了错综复杂的煤气管道系统
Details surrounding the intricate system of gas lines
其中大部分管道的历史
that run beneath the square are still forthcoming,
可以追溯到苏联时期
but the majority of those lines date back to the Soviet era
这些管道至少有三十多年没有更新过了
and have not been updated in at least. ..
安娜 安娜 我在想...
Anna... Anna. .. I've been thinking...
看上去 我们...
It looks like we...
我们出城待上几天吧
We should leave town for a couple of days.
带上亚历克斯去度假
Alex, you, me. Vacations.
- 现在吗？ - 马上走
- Now?    - Tonight.
你们为什么说英语？
Why are you speaking in English?
就...
Just...
就我们三个人
Just the three of us.
这起爆炸可能并不是事故 而是一次有预谋的袭击
...may not have been an accident, but a targeted attack.
在这起爆炸中受伤的人数和损失情况
Preliminary numbers are just starting. ..
那我们去哪儿？
Where will we go?
很快就会统计出来
...to come in regarding those wounded in the blast.
我们目前能确认有十一名
We can confirm that 11 tourists...
利奥尼德
Leonid?
国籍尚不清楚的游客
their nationalities still unconfirmed,
已经在第一时间被送往附近医院接受治疗
have been transported to area hospitals for treatment.
尽管俄罗斯官方目前仍然将此事件归咎于煤气总管爆裂
While Russian officials continue to blame a gas-main break,
但有专家称 从爆炸区域的形状和残骸的大小来看
experts are citing the shape of the blast area and the size of the debris field
这更像是一起有预谋的爆炸
as more consistent with that of a set explosive,
专家推测 这可能是一次有组织的秘密破坏行动
leading to speculation that this may have been an undeclared act of aggression.
尽管俄罗斯国防部坚持称这是一起事故
Although the Defense Ministry is maintaining that this is strictly an accident. ..
安娜 快帮亚历克斯收拾行李
Anna, pack a bag for Alex.
我们现在就走
We're leaving now.
安娜 安娜
Anya! Anya!
我们有活要干
We have work to do.
部长先生
Mr. Secretary.
我不知道你在俄罗斯
I wasn't aware you were in Russia.
我不在 克里姆林宫被炸了 我得赶紧走
I'm not. Not since a bomb blew up the Kremlin.
昨天我飞到这里 来接受俄罗斯总理颁发的友好勋章
Yesterday I flew in to accept the Order of Friendship from the Russian Prime Minister.
现在我得飞回华盛顿
Now I'm headed back to Washington
向总统递交辞职书
to hand the President my resignation.
我的首席参谋威廉·勃兰特
My Chief Analyst, William Brandt.
有笔吗？
Do you have a pen?
- 什么？  - 笔
- Pardon me?  - A pen.
有
Yeah.
克里姆林宫里发生了什么？
Ethan, what happened in the Kremlin?
他是参谋吗？
Chief Analyst, you say?
你想说我的判断有问题
If you're implying that I made a bad call...
欧洲男子
European male.
五十多岁 6英尺 180磅 蓝眼睛
Fifties. About six-foot, 180 pounds. Blue eyes.
他是谁
Who is he?
画得很粗糙 不过根据描述
A crude drawing, but by your description,
可能是库尔特·亨德里克斯
that could be Kurt Hendricks.
智商190 在瑞典特种部队服过役
190 IQ. Served in Swedish Special Forces.
斯德哥尔摩大学物理学教授
Professor of physics, Stockholm University.
专门研究核残局理论
Specialist in nuclear endgame theory.
因为他太疯狂
Asked to resign...
所以被迫辞职
Well, because he's crazy.
克伯特
Cobalt.
你得警告克里姆林宫
You have to alert the Kremlin that one of their strategists
克伯特手上有核弹发射装置
has a nuclear launch device
他的手下已经拿到了启动密码
and one of his operatives has the codes to activate it.
你凭什么这么说？
And what makes you say that?
我看到他了
I saw him
从军械库里出来 手里拿了个包
leaving the executive armory, bag in hand.
为了掩盖行踪 他引发了爆炸
He set off that explosion to cover his tracks.
俄罗斯人几星期之后才会发现
It could be weeks before the Russians know it's missing.
得告诉他们
Unless we tell them.
他们不会相信的
They won't listen to us.
俄罗斯人一定认为是我们炸了克里姆林宫
As far as the Russians are concerned, we just bombed the Kremlin.
要知道 自从古巴导弹危机以来
The tension between the United States and Russia
美俄关系还从来没有这么紧张过
hasn't been this high since the Cuban Missile Crisis.
不论对错 现在矛头都指向IMF
And the blame, right or wrong, points to IMF.
总统已经签署执行幽灵协议
The President has initiated Ghost Protocol.
现在IMF不存在了
The entire IMF has been disavowed.
那接下来呢？
So what happens now?
听着 上面要我把你带回华盛顿
Now, I've been ordered to take you back to Washington,
国防部会把你诬陷成疯狂的极端分子
where the DOD will label you as a rogue extremist
把爆炸案的责任全都归在你身上
and hang the Kremlin bombing on you and your team.
除非...
Unless,
你在从这里去飞机场的路上...
you were to escape somewhere between here and the airport,
攻击了我和勃兰特 然后逃跑
having assaulted Mr. Brandt and me.
先生？
Sir?
你会从一个我不知道的备用藏身处里
You would then illegally scrounge whatever material you could
抢走武器和设备 你的队员也会出现在那里
from a backup supply cache that I've overlooked.
等待你的进一步行动指示
The same cache where your team are waiting for further orders.
先生 你可能...
Sir, you may want to...
然后你会消失 这次对话也从来没有发生过
You will then disappear, and this conversation never having taken place,
没有任何人知道你的目的
your intentions would be unclear.
不过 一旦你队里有人被抓或被杀
But if any one of your team is caught or killed,
那他们将会被定性为"煽动全球性核战的恐怖分子"
they will be branded terrorists, out to incite global nuclear war.
你将决定是否接受这个任务
Your mission, should you choose to accept it.
伊森 你是我最好的特工
Ethan, you were my best man.
很抱歉你牺牲这么多
And I'm sorry it's come to this,
却落得这么一个结果
after all the sacrifices you made.
但是我希望你明白
If we don't meet again, I just want you to know,
我一直把你当朋友
I've always considered you a friend.
趴下 开快点 开快点
Stay down! Drive, drive, drive!
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
吸口气 跟着我
Take a deep breath. Stay with me.
- 好了吗？ - 嗯
- Ready?   - Yeah.
怎么办？
What do we do?
你等在这儿
Wait here.
我还能去哪儿？
Where else am I going to go?
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
嗨 嗨 那边有人
停止射击 停止射击
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
给我停止射击
Hold your fire!
把枪放下
Weapons down!
你们到底在打什么？
What are you firing at?
都把枪放下 见鬼
今天有两个犯人从兰卡监狱越狱了 头儿
Two prisoners escaped from Rankow Prison today.
(谢尔盖)
(波格丹)
这个人...
And this one?...
去查一查
What do we know about him?
为什么会管用？
Why would that work?
你指什么？
Why would what work?
尸体加照明弹 为什么会管用？
The flare on the body, why would that work?
当然管用
It did work.
- 我知道 可是...   - 嘿
- Yeah, I know, but... - Hey!
为什么呢？你怎么知道那会吸引火力？
But why? I mean, how did you know that would draw their fire?
不知道 我赌了一把
I didn't. I played a hunch.
好吧 那你的设想是什么？
Okay. All right, so what was your scenario?
一个人在水里被岸上人射击
Right, you. .. There's a guy being shot at in the water.
突然决定点燃一个照明弹游来游去
All of a sudden, decides to light up a flare and swim around?
你认为敌人会怎么想？
I mean, what did you assume they'd be thinking?
- 怎么想？ - 对
- Thinking?   - Yeah.
我认为他们不会想
I didn't assume they were thinking.
他们会朝一切活动物体射击
I assumed they were shooting at anything that moved.
所以我给了他们一个目标
I just gave them a target. Look, these...
他们没你想得那么多 伙计
These guys aren't Rhodes Scholars, you know?
部长死了 是吗？
It's really happening, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
好 行了 听到这声音吗？
Okay, you know what that sound is?
我们的车来了
That's our ride out of here!
是绿色车厢 47号
All right, it's a green car. Number 47.
我看见了
I see green!
走 快点
Okay, let's do it.
快 快 快
Go, go, go, go.
找找 47
All right, 47.
我没找到
I don't see it.
47.
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit!
哇哦
Whoa! Ho!
就是它 载货单
This is it. The manifest.
请输入密码
Enter your code.
嗷！
Pole!
啊！
Ah!
呀...
Jeez...
请按确认
Press enter.
视网膜扫描
Retinal scanner!
嗯？
Huh?
视网膜扫描
Retinal scan required.
小心
Watch out!
视网膜扫描
Retinal scan required.
特工确认
Agent confirmed.
伊森？天呐 我以为你死了
Ethan? Jeez, I thought you were dead!
- 差不多  - 这是谁？
- We are.  - Who's this?
这是班吉和简 威廉·勃兰特 他是参谋
Agents Dunn and Carter. William Brandt, Chief Analyst.
参谋？
Analyst?
(载入中)
特工确认
Agent confirmed.
(伊森·亨特的任务指南)
世界最终会怎样毁灭？
How will the world finally end?
我的工作就是预知未来
It is my job to predict the unthinkable.
把数十亿人的生死当作一局棋
To treat the death of billions as a game.
这样过了二十年 我麻木了
After 20 years of this, I was numb.
直到我想到了一个新的问题
Until a new question crossed my mind.
全世界毁灭之后会怎么样？
What happens after the end of the world?
你这条线路安全吗？
Are you sure your line is secure?
每两百或三百万年...
Every two or three million years...
你确定这条线路安全吗？
Are you certain your line is secure?
总会有大灾难毁灭地球上的所有生物
some natural catastrophe devastates all life on Earth.
可生命在继续
But life goes on.
存活下来的生命变得强大
And what little remains is made stronger.
简单地说 世界毁灭虽然很可怕
Put simply, world destruction is an unpleasant,
但它是进化的一部分
but necessary part of evolution.
我很好奇当人类面对...
What happens then, I wondered,
下一个世界末日时会发生什么
when mankind faces the next end of the world?
我不管你用什么样的方法 把他弄到迪拜
I don't care what you have to do to get him to Dubai.
我会让他不虚此行的
I'll make it worth his while. Just do it.
我观察过广岛 长崎
I looked to Hiroshima, Nagasaki...
我等你电话
I'll be waiting for your call.
废墟上重建起繁荣的城市
thriving cities rebuilt from the ashes,
人们为此建起纪念碑
monuments to the unimaginable,
并从中懂得了和平的意义
dedicated to the concept of peace.
这让我想到 也许核战争能成为自然秩序的一个部分
It occurred to me here that nuclear war might have a place in the natural order.
只要它能被人类所控制
But only if it could be controlled.
只要它能平等地触动每个人
Only if it touched every living soul equally.
IMF认为这个男人 库尔特·亨德里克斯
IMF now believes this man, Kurt Hendricks,
是个核极端分子 代号克伯特
is the nuclear extremist, code name Cobalt.
今天有人看见他带着核弹发射装置离开克里姆林宫
Today he was seen leaving the Kremlin, with what is likely a nuclear launch device.
两天前 萨宾·莫洛在布达佩斯杀了我们的特工
Two days ago, Sabine Moreau killed one of our agents in Budapest
抢走了俄罗斯核弹发射密码
and relieved him of Russian nuclear launch codes.
情报说 她在36小时后会入住迪拜哈里发塔的酒店
Intel indicates she will check into the Burj Hotel in Dubai in 36 hours.
马吕斯·维斯特伦是克伯特的助手
Marius Wistrom is a known operative of Cobalt.
维斯特正在去迪拜的路上
Wistrom is currently en route to Dubai.
想要使用发射装置 克伯特需要得到启动密码
For the launch device to work, Cobalt needs the activation codes.
所以他派维斯特伦去向莫洛买密码
He's sending Wistrom to buy them from Moreau.
我们的部长...
The Secretary...
死了
is dead.
总统签署执行了幽灵协议
The President has invoked Ghost Protocol.
我们什么都没了
We're shut down.
没卫星 没安全屋 没供给 没支援
No satellite, safe house, support, or extraction.
我们四个和车里的这些设备
The four of us and the contents of this car
是IMF仅存的战斗力
are all that remain of the IMF.
从现在起 没有人批准任何行动 如果要退出
And as of this moment, any action is unsanctioned. So if you want out,
马上开口
speak now.
目标是亨德里克斯
Our mission is Hendricks.
现在只有我们能阻止他
We're all that stands between him and his goal.
所以不能有半点疏忽
Nothing can be left to chance.
一切和他有关系的人...
Everyone connected with this man...
都对我们寻找目标具有很高的情报价值
is considered an asset with valuable information about our target.
没人知道我们还在工作
No one can know we're still on line.
他一旦逃跑 就抓不到了
We lose Hendricks now, we lose him forever.
说说 什么计划？
So, what's the play?
36小时后 维斯特伦会从莫洛那儿拿到密码
Wistrom will take delivery from Moreau in 36 hours.
我们不能让他离开酒店
Now we cannot let the launch codes leave the hotel,
但我们要靠他找到亨德里克斯
but we need Wistrom to lead us to Hendricks.
只有拿到密码他才会回去
He'll only do that if he has the codes.
或者他以为他拿到了
Or if he thinks he has them.
我们的计划就是拦截交易
Our objective is to intercept the sale,
然后把密码掉包
replace the authentic codes with counterfeits
跟踪维斯特伦 找到亨德里克斯
and follow Wistrom to Hendricks.
行啊 很简单
Well, that's simple enough.
我们偷走真密码 留下个山寨的
We snatch the codes, we gin up some fakes.
简 你扮成莫洛 把假密码卖给维斯特伦 大功告成
Jane, you double Moreau, and sell the codes to Wistrom and Bob's your uncle.
那么 我们要怎么做才能从莫洛那里偷走密码呢？
And how do you propose we just snatch the codes from Moreau?
把她做掉
We take her out.
对 做掉她 不过得偷偷地
Yeah, we take her out. But, you know, discreetly.
偷偷地？
Discreetly?
对
Yeah.
她还有用 得留着她 抱歉 我差点忘了
Right, she's an asset. Right. I get it. Sorry. Nothing left to chance.
我刚才就是随口一说 别把我的话当真
He said. .. I'm spitballing. It's not all gonna be gold.
- 不能动维斯特伦  - 行啊
- We don't touch Wistrom. - All right.
莫洛也是
Or Moreau.
她要为哈纳韦的死负责 不过我们得先解决亨德里克斯
She'll answer for Hanaway, but it has to be when I say. After we hit Hendricks.
只带必需品
Only pack what we need.
没错 不过多带点备着也好
Yeah, absolutely. Only pack what we... You never know.
(阿联酋  迪拜)
就算我们能冒充维斯特伦和莫洛...
So even if we can double Wistrom and Moreau,
怎么让他们待在不同的房间..
how do we keep them in separate rooms
却以为在同一个房间里？
while having them think that they're in the same room?
我们要给酒店整整容
We give the hotel a facelift.
维斯特伦会以为他到了莫洛的套房
Wistrom will think he's arriving at Moreau's suite,
可实际上他进的是假冒的房间
but, really, he'll be walking into our decoy room.
我会等在那里
Where I'll double Moreau.
楼下 班吉装成维斯特伦
Downstairs, Benji will double Wistrom.
戴面具
Masks!
和真的莫洛见面
And meet with the real Moreau.
好的
And, uh. ..
那我干什么？
What am I doing?
你？你做助手
You? You're the helper!
助手 好吧
Helper. That's great.
如果我没理解错的话 你们要去...
Okay, so to the extent I understand what you're talking about here. ..
世界上最高的摩天大楼哈里发塔
The Burj Khalifa, it's the tallest building in the world,
改变它的建筑结构
and you want to alter its infrastructure
让两个人以为他们在那儿见了面
with the hopes of convincing two people that they've
可实际上他们并没有真的碰面
had a meeting, which actually really never happened.
对吗？
Right?
是骆驼
Camels.
你到干洗间了吗？
ETA on dry cleaning.
已经到了
On my way up.
离敲门还有34分钟
Okay, 34 minutes to door knock.
喔...
Wow, um. ..
听着 我这里稍微有点小麻烦 不过不用太担心
Okay, this is a slight wrinkle, but nothing to worry about.
只不过我们得从大楼外面进入服务器机房
We're just going to have to go into the server room from the outside.
什么？
What?
这里的服务器的防火墙是军用级别的
Well, the firewalls on this building's server are military grade.
要是我能联系到总部的约瑟夫
I mean, this would be a cinch
就能轻而易举地搞定
if I could call Youssef back at headquarters,
不过约瑟夫已经不存在了 我们也是
but Youssef doesn't exist anymore, and neither do we.
能黑进去 可很费时间
I could hack it, but it would take too long.
硬接线呢
Then hardwire in.
要想进入机房 得通过四层最先进的安全网
And there's four layers of next-gen security between us and the server room.
根本没办法从大门进去
There's no way we can get to it from inside.
进不了服务器 就没办法控制电梯
If we can't get to the server, we don't control the elevators,
也没办法控制监控摄像头
we don't control the security cameras.
计划还没开始就泡汤了
This operation is over before it even begins.
我说了 我们可以从大楼外面进去
I'm telling you, we can get to it from outside.
"我们"？
"We"?
我...我操作电脑
I'm. .. I'm on the computer.
我只是个...
I'm just, uh. ..
助手
The helper.
好吧 机房在几楼？
What floor is it on?
在130楼
Oh, 130.
130楼？
130?
- 通风管  - 压敏材料
- Vent ducts. - Pressure sensitive.
来不及搞定
Not enough time.
- 电梯井  - 红外探测
- Elevator shaft. - Infrared sensors.
也搞不定
Not enough time.
那该怎么办？
How am I supposed to do this?
见鬼
God damn it!
噢 真高啊
Oh, that's high.
记住 你的手只要滚动一下就会消除吸力
Okay, now remember, it's a rolling off motion that disengages the bond.
灯是蓝的 就是吸住了
When the meter is blue, that's full adhesion.
很容易记 蓝色 吸住
Easy way to remember, blue is glue.
- 那红色呢？ - 死了
- And when it's red?   - Dead.
这个是刀具 还有服务器的接口
Here's your cutter, okay? And your server interface.
帮你放背后 一 二
Both going back here. One, two.
机房在上面的第十一层 右边第七间
Okay, Ethan, the hotel server is eleven stories up and seven units over.
行吗？通讯检查
Okay? Comm check.
好 收到
Yeah. Copy.
那么...
So. ..
离敲门还有26分钟
It's 26 minutes to door knock.
好的
Yeah.
还有25分钟
25 minutes to door knock.
那是什么？
What the hell is that?
是啊 那是怎么回事？
Yeah, what the hell is that?
是沙暴
It's a sandstorm.
距离还很远
It's a long way off, Ethan.
应该没问题
Shouldn't be a problem.
还有24分钟
24 minutes to door knock.
伊森在哪儿？
Where's Ethan?
这不是真的吧？
You've got to be kidding me.
还有23分钟
23 minutes to door knock.
到目标楼层了
I'm at server level.
还有22分钟
22 minutes to door knock.
倒计时 帮不上忙
The countdown is not helping.
我是着急
I'm just saying.
进去了
I'm in.
很好 伊森 胜利在望了
That's great, Ethan. You're halfway home.
定位服务器
Located server.
如果连上了 告诉我
Please tell me we're online.
好 我们连上了
All right, we're live.
好了 这下电梯和监控摄像头全在我掌控之中了
Okay, I now have control of the elevators and the security cameras.
准备装修
Time to redecorate.
你来操作 盯着维斯特伦和莫洛
Okay, you drive. And look out for Wistrom and Moreau.
莫洛提前进电梯了
Moreau is at the elevators ahead of schedule.
快去
Go.
这个门打不开 是吗？
We can't open this door, can we?
门？是的
The door? No.
伊森 你得回到这儿来
Ethan, you gotta get down here now.
伊森
Ethan!
有问题吗 伊森？
Is there a problem? Ethan?
赶不上了
We're not gonna make it.
必须赶上
We have to make it.
伊森在哪儿？
Where's Ethan?
你的绳子不够长
Your line's not long enough!
还用你说
No shit!
虽然有难度
That was not easy,
不过 搞定了
but I did it.
我错过什么了？
What'd I miss?
镜头可能会让眼睛有点不舒服
The lens might be a little uncomfortable.
它会把捕捉到的图像传到箱子里的打印机上
It captures images and transmits them to the printer in the briefcase.
- 行了吗？ - 嗯
- All right?   - Mmm.
一只眼睛看不见 不过没事
I can't see out of one eye, but I'm fine.
连眨两下就是快门
Blink twice to activate the shutter.
数字是按顺序排的
Notice the numbers are in order?
完美的拷贝
A perfect copy.
数字被打乱了
But the numbers are scrambled.
面具呢？
Masks?
还要60秒 你确定我不用戴面具吗？
60 seconds. You sure I shouldn't wear a mask?
我看着一点儿也不像阿拉伯人
You know, 'cause I'm not exactly Omar Sharif.
我装法国人 这是追踪器
I'll play it French. This is your tracking device.
- 这是追踪目标  - 回形针？
- This is what you're tracking. - The paper clip?
不 是纸
No, it's the paper.
我们在公文箱里的纸上涂上同位素
It's in the briefcase. It's coated with isotopes which give off a unique...
这样 就算文件换到别的包里 你也能追踪到
It just means that you can track the documents even if they switch briefcases.
多大范围？
Range?
不是很大 才半英里
Not that good. It's, like, half a mile.
所以 不能让维斯特伦离开你的视线
Safest thing to do would be not let Wistrom out of your sight.
那是他吗？
Is that Wistrom?
那是谁？
Who's that with him?
不知道 没有数据库 没法做面部识别
I don't know. We don't have an uplink, so there's no facial recognition.
他是谁？
Who's that with him?
利奥尼德·李森科 密码破译员
That's Leonid Lisenker. Polish-born cryptographer.
冷战后 他重新设计了俄罗斯核安全系统
He redesigned Russia's nuclear security after the Cold War.
他是来鉴定发射密码的
He's here to authenticate the launch codes.
- 我们暴露了  - 这不可能
- Yes, he is. We are blown.  - No, we're not blown.
他一看到伪造的密码 我们就暴露了
Well, we will be as soon as he sees the counterfeit launch codes.
不会的
We're not blown.
进电梯了
He's in the elevator.
拖住他们
Delay them.
重新编程需要多久？
Benji, how long would it take you to reprogram the case?
几秒钟 你要干嘛？
A couple of seconds. What for, though?
我们做个真的密码拷贝
To make an exact copy of the launch codes.
- 什么？ - 这可不行
- What?  - You can't do that.
- 到22楼了  - 拖住他
- Wistrom's on 22! - Slow him down.
我尽力而为
I'll do what I can.
你刚才说要干什么 伊森？
Wait, wait. Ethan, hang on now!
等一下 你等一下
Hang on. Just a second.
难道你想把真的核弹发射密码交给维斯特伦？
You're talking about handing over active nuclear launch codes to Wistrom?
是的 我们重新编程
Yes. Reprogram the case.
听着...停!
Listen... Stop!
你知道自己在说什么吗？
Just listen to what you're saying.
你走火入魔了 脑子不清楚
You're fixating. You're not thinking clearly.
不行 绝对不行 我不允许
It's not gonna happen. I won't let it!
到33楼了
33 and climbing!
勃兰特 好好想想
Brandt, use your head now.
目标不是密码 是亨德里克斯
The mission is not the codes, the mission is Hendricks.
给他假密码 让他无法启动装置
Then just let it play out. Give him bad codes. Neutralize him.
这没用
You know that won't do it.
对恐怖分子来说 失败不过是成功的彩排
Failure to a terrorist is just a rehearsal for success.
41楼了
41!
今天让他跑了 明天他又会出现在别的地方接着干
We lose Hendricks today, he shows up somewhere else tomorrow. He finds another way.
再也没有人会阻止他
With no IMF to stop him.
我们就这一次机会 快把箱子给我
No. It's now or never. Now, Brandt, give me the case.
你说的 我们绝不能有半点疏忽
Nothing can be left to chance. You said that.
你是参谋
You're the analyst.
你告诉我 他再没有别的机会拿到密码
Now, tell me there's not another way for Hendricks to get those codes.
50楼
50!
告诉我 今天来这里是他唯一的选择
You tell me that this is his only avenue, right here, right now, today.
如果是这样 那我就放弃
You tell me that, I'll walk away.
- 不要了  - 不戴面具了吗？
- We go without.  - Without masks?
- 简 该走了  - 伊森
- Jane needs to go.   - Ethan!
没别的办法
We have no choice.
你去见莫洛 就不能带武器
Ethan, you'd be walking in on Moreau unarmed.
要是你被认出来...
Face-first. Literally.
谁说他们见过？
How do we know they've met?
- 万一见过呢？ - 无所谓
- How do we know they haven't? - Doesn't matter!
该死的
Damn it.
只能走这步了
We have no choice.
护目镜
Goggles.
万一他们见过呢？
What if they have met?
请进
Come in.
你们谁是维斯特伦？
Which one of you is Wistrom?
我是
I am.
我很欣赏你的工作
I admire your work.
坐吧
Sit.
密码在哪儿？
Where are my codes?
钻石在哪儿？
Where are my diamonds?
在附近
Close by.
我的报酬呢？
You have my payment?
给我密码 就给你报酬
When I see the codes.
别紧张 请进
Not to worry. Come in!
先喝杯茶吧
I thought we could have tea.
莫洛小姐 先生们
Mademoiselle. Messieurs.
先给钻石 再给密码
No diamonds, no codes.
先给密码 再给钻石
No codes, no diamonds.
杀了他
Kill this one.
别激动嘛
We didn't come alone.
走廊里有我们的狙击手
That hallway out there is a kill-box.
你知道我们老板
You know who we work for.
拿不到密码 我们就回不去
We come back with the codes, or we don't come back.
那些狙击手怎么样？
How good is your backup?
最好的
The best.
哦
Hmm.
最好的已经被我杀了
I've killed the best.
要不要加点糖？
Do you care for some sugar?
行了 说正事吧
Enough. Let's get this done.
你要报酬 而我要保证
You want payment, I want guarantees.
等他验证了密码
When he's authenticated the codes,
我会打电话给你钻石
I'll make the call and you get your diamonds.
要不然...
That or...
我们都没好结果
we all go home in buckets.
谁也别想活着出去
Nobody leaves this hotel alive.
把文件拿来
Get the papers.
有问题吗？
Is there a problem?
锁住了
It's locked.
哦 请原谅 一定有钥匙
Ah, forgive me. There must be a key.
稍等一下
One moment, huh?
小姐
Messieurs.
我搞错了 是用密码开的 不是钥匙
My mistake. It is a combination, not a key.
你告诉我数字
You tell me the numbers.
没问题
They're good.
0 0 0
Zero Zero Zero.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
和你们做生意很愉快
It was a pleasure doing business with...
维斯特伦拿到密码走了
Wistrom has the launch codes. He's on the move.
我已经照你说的做了 现在 快放了我的家人吧
Hey, I did as you asked. I did. Now let my family go!
放了利奥尼德的家人
Release Leonid's family.
谢谢上帝
Thank God.
你可以去见上帝了
You can thank him in person.
和你们做生意很愉快
It was a pleasure doing business with you.
杀了他
Kill him!
莫洛跑了
Moreau's on the move!
我来对付
I've got her.
简？
Jane?
她还有用
She's an asset!
一定要抓活的
I need her alive!
快回答
Acknowledge!
伊森 维斯特伦在电梯里 我没看见利奥尼德
Uh, Ethan, Wistrom is in the elevator. I can't see Leonid, though.
收到 拖住他 给我弄部电梯
Benji, slow him down. Get me an elevator.
去找利奥尼德
Find Leonid.
我锁定维斯特伦了 但我不确定
Benji, I've got a lock on Wistrom. But I can't tell.
他还在电梯里吗
Is he still in the elevator?
他在 还在电梯里
班吉
Benji?
伊森 回话
Ethan. Over?
班吉
Benji.
班吉 我听不见
Benji, I lost...
伊森 能听见吗？
Ethan, can you hear me?
能听见吗？完毕
Ethan, can you hear me? Over.
天呐
Jesus!
坐下
Sit down!
- 看着她  - 干嘛叫我？
- Watch her.  - Why me?
因为我会杀了她
Because if I do, I'll kill her.
站住 我的队长
Hold it, Team Leader.
你没想到 我会一直追到这儿吧
Did you really think I wouldn't catch up with you?
我们不是敌人 那是个圈套
You and I are not enemies. It was a set-up...
你的谎言很快就会被揭穿
We'll find out your lies soon enough.
快走
Move it!
那就对不起了
I'm sorry about this.
利奥尼德 班吉？
Leonid. Benji?
你找班吉？
Go for Benji.
找到利奥尼德了 他中枪了
I've got Leonid by the elevators. He's been shot.
什么？
What?
坚持住 坚持住
Hey, hey. Stay with me. Stay with me.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
简 不
Jane! No!
(无信号)
(信号锁定)
拜托 拜托
Come on. Come on.
天呐 风太大了
那是我的车
他把我的车开走了
简 莫洛做了什么？
Now, what happened with Moreau, Jane?
她不肯帮我们找亨德里克斯
She couldn't help us with Hendricks.
所以你就把她推出去了
So let's throw her off the building!
我没有推她
I didn't throw her.
你把她踢出去了
Let's throw her off the building!
这不是你的任务 简
She was not the mission, Jane!
你的任务是追踪那份文件 找到亨德里克斯 而他现在跑了
The mission was to track the file back to Hendricks, who is in the wind
手里拿着发射密码
with nuclear launch codes!
你可能没注意到她拿枪对着我
Maybe you didn't notice the gun she had pointed at me.
就像你没有注意到窗子开着
Yeah, like you didn't notice the open window,
而我们又在那么高的地方
or that we're about a mile up in the air!
我踢她是本能反应
It was an instinctive move.
别跟我狡辩
It doesn't matter!
我们现在面临核战争
We're talking about a nuclear war.
莫洛比你重要得多
The asset is more important than you.
你凭什么对我的动作指手画脚？
Where do you get off telling me how well I executed?
你以为自己是谁
We inherited you.
你不过就是个官僚
You're just a bureaucrat!
希望是好消息 他来了？
Better have good news for me. Is he here?
我需要告诉你这次的任务是什么吗？
You think I need you to tell me what the mission is?
好的 登喜路打火机 我会去的
Yeah, I got it. Dunhill lighter. I'll be there.
不会有人跟踪我
And no one will be following me.
你自己小心 别被人跟踪
Just make sure no one's following you.
那些俄罗斯人怎么找到我们的？
And how the hell did the Russians find us?
- 你问我干嘛？ - 因为你负责通讯
- What are you asking me for?  - Because you're communications!
你负责掩盖我们的行踪
You're in charge of covering our tracks.
班吉 你绝不能再犯这样的错误了
You cannot afford to make mistakes like that now, Benji.
你已经不是技术员了 你是专业特工
You're not a technician anymore. You're a field agent.
而你只是个"参谋"
And you're just an "analyst."
对吗？
Right?
你到底是谁 勃兰特？
Who are you really, Brandt?
- 什么意思？ - 什么意思？
- What are you asking?   - What am I asking?
那我换个方式吧
Let me see if I can put it another way.
一个身手这么好的特工 怎么会是个参谋？
How does an agent with skills like that end up an analyst?
我们都有秘密
Well, we all have our secrets.
不是吗？
Don't we, Ethan?
你把你的说出来 我把我的告诉你
You tell me yours, I'll tell you mine.
(屏蔽 无人跟踪)
等在这儿 我去见个朋友
I have friends in the region. Just sit tight.
我找人送你们出去
I'll send someone to get you out of here.
亨德里克斯呢？你的计划？
What about Hendricks? What's the plan?
原计划是我们一起阻止他
The plan was for us to stop him together.
那现在怎么办？
Well, what are you going to do?
改变原计划
Change the plan.
等等 这就完了？
Wait. That's it?
你要单枪匹马去找他？
What are you going to do, go after him alone?
你到底是什么人 勃兰特？
Would you care to explain yourself, Agent Brandt?
我曾经去一个国家执行任务
I was on a protection detail in Croatia.
秘密保护线人 一对夫妇
Shadowing the assets, husband and wife.
他们不知道我们的存在
They were never supposed to know we were there.
这只是一个常规任务
Whole thing's routine, it was a milk run.
三天后
Three days in
我们听说有一群外国杀手要来杀他们
we caught wind that a Serbian hit squad was after our couple.
不过我的团队掌握主动权
But my team had it under control.
我们知道他们要来
We knew they were coming.
可是我总是有点担心 我觉得应该警告这对夫妇
But I couldn't shake this feeling that I should warn the couple somehow.
让他们有个心理准备
I wanted to find a way to let them know.
不过上头有规矩 所以我没说
But, you know, orders are orders, so I didn't.
有一天 那个丈夫想离开饭店 出去跑跑步
One day, the husband decides to leave the hotel and go for a run,
于是我跟着他 我让两个队友照看他妻子
so I follow him, and I leave two men with the wife.
等我回来 队友昏迷不醒 妻子不见了
When I get back, my guys are unconscious and the wife is gone.
三天后 警察发现了她的尸体
Local police found her body three days later.
只剩一部分了
What was left of her, anyway.
后来我就不干了
That was my last day in the field.
我没有办法面对这种生死攸关的情况
I couldn't face another life-or-death situation after that.
那丈夫后来怎么样了？
So what happened to the husband?
没再见到他
I never saw him again.
直到两天前在莫斯科
Until two days ago in Moscow,
部长把伊森·亨特介绍给我
when the Secretary introduced me to Ethan Hunt.
不对吧 我听说朱莉娅甩了他
No, that's not what happened. She left him.
是的 我也听到过
Yeah, I heard that one, too, Benji.
可是很遗憾 我当时在场
But, unfortunately, I was there.
部长接到电话的时候 我就在旁边
Just like I was there when the Secretary got the phone call
伊森因为极其残酷地杀害了六个外国人被抓起来
that Ethan was in custody for killing six Serbian nationals in cold blood.
未经批准杀人
An unsanctioned hit.
是
Yeah.
原来是这样
Disavowed.
再后来 我稀里糊涂到了迪拜
The next thing I know, I'm on a plane to Dubai,
我一直在犹豫要不要说
wondering the whole time, do I tell him?
我该怎么说
How do I tell him?
是我的责任
That I'm responsible.
我能警告他的
I could have warned him.
我应该警告他
I should have warned him.
可我没有
But I didn't.
人死了
And she died.
谢尔盖 谢尔盖 我的朋友
Sergei! Sergei, my friend!
我说过我会带他来的 没错吧
I told you I would get him here. Didn't I say?
真的是他？
How do I know it's him?
就是他 你相信我 我相信你 对吗
Yes, it's him. You trust me, I trust you. Right?
就是这个人
This is the guy!
就是他救了我 我跟你说过的
This is the guy, the one I told you about.
行了 可以把这个打开了
So we can take these things off.
对不起 他是个好人 不过他不像我这么了解你
Sorry. He's a great guy, but he doesn't know you like I do.
听说 你为美国政府工作
So, you work for the American government.
你是军火商
And you're an arms dealer.
不 不 不 谢尔盖 谢尔盖
No, no, no. Sergei. Sergei.
他是"独立的防御协调人" 对吗？
He's "independent defense coordinator." Right?
这是份很高尚的工作
That you are. Very classy job.
听着 他是我朋友
Listen. He's a friend.
钻石是给波格丹的
Those diamonds are for Bogdan.
不用 无所谓 都给你
No, no. It's okay. You can have them.
你和我堂兄之间有什么协议 那是你们的事
Whatever arrangements you made with my cousin is between you and him.
找我买东西 就得付钱
You want something from me, you pay.
我想你误会了 我不是买 是卖
You misunderstand. I'm not buying. I'm selling.
你要卖
You're selling.
卖什么？
Selling what?
未来
The future.
那个我自己有 谢谢
Yeah, I got all I need, thank you.
我们两国在战争的边缘
Our countries are on the brink of war.
打仗好啊 我能发财
War is very good for business.
核战争呢？
Nuclear war?
说下去
Go on.
我在找库尔特·亨德里克斯
I'm looking for a man named Kurt Hendricks.
你可能听说过他
You may know him as Cobalt.
你应该知道他想要什么
In either case, I think you know what he wants.
我猜他以前八成找你买过
I'll bet he even tried to buy it from you at some point.
说下去
Go on.
他拿到箱子 拿到密码
He has a case, he has codes.
现在就缺一颗战术通讯卫星
But they're worthless without a tactical satellite.
我想知道他从哪儿能搞到
I want to know where he'd get it.
知道这种情报的人通常是潜在的恐怖分子
A man with information like that would be a potential terrorist.
对你们政府来说
And to your government,
潜在的恐怖分子等于恐怖分子
a potential terrorist is a terrorist.
你肯帮我
If you help me,
我的朋友就是你的朋友
my friends become your friends.
抱歉
Sorry.
我不能帮你
I cannot help you.
我绝不会告诉你 俄罗斯曾经悄悄地卖了...
I certainly cannot tell you that Russia quietly sold...
一个淘汰的战术通讯卫星给孟买的电信公司
an obsolete tactical satellite to a certain telecom in Mumbai.
是谁出的主意？
And whoever gave them that idea?
某个独立的第三方
An enterprising third party.
防御协调人
Working on commission.
帮助老朋友 结交新朋友
Helping old friends. Making new ones.
卫星能关闭吗？
Can the satellite be shut down?
这需要专业技术
That would take special skills,
一个人可干不了
and you cannot do it alone.
这些是什么？
What's in the bags?
我们的装备
It's our gear.
怎么弄到的？
How'd you get it?
交了个朋友
Made a friend.
我们能帮忙了
Well, I'm glad we could help.
现在可以了
You could help now.
听着 伊森 我们之前...
Look, Ethan, before we...
过去的就让它过去吧
Whatever happened, happened.
我们还有机会补救 不过 得赶快行动
We still have a chance to clean this up, but we have to do it now.
而且要一起行动
And we have to do it together.
我们要去哪儿？
Okay. So, where are we going?
印度
India.
- 印度？ - 对
- India? India?  - Sure.
没问题
Okay. Great.
这飞机真酷
Love the jet.
你还没看见车呢
Wait till you see the car.
席德洛夫
Sidorov.
你好啊 老朋友
How have you been, old friend?
啊 是你啊
Oh, it's you.
我最近一直在忙别的案子
I've been busy with other things.
不过 我很快就会去抓你的
But I'll be after you again soon enough.
我知道你在找一个美国人
I understand you're looking for an American. ..
是的
I am.
你还在找一个两天前被人从克里姆林宫偷走的核弹发射装置
You're also looking for a nuclear launch device stolen from the Kremlin two days ago.
是吗？
I am?
我有办法让你一箭双雕
I can help you find both.
只要我们能达成共识
If... we can come to an understanding.
布瑞吉·纳特
Brij Nath.
花花公子 传媒大亨
Brij Nath. Playboy. Multimedia tycoon.
表面上看他的整个网络很先进
On the surface, his entire network is state-of-the-art.
其实是用非法购买的冷战旧货改装的 包括这颗卫星
But it's built on illegally acquired Cold War cast-offs, including this, the Novosti satellite.
亨德里克斯要用它发射核弹
Hendricks needs it to launch a nuclear strike,
要赶在他之前把这颗卫星关闭
and we have to shut it down before he gets that chance.
要关闭卫星 就得弄到接入代码
And to do that, we need to get the access code from him.
这要靠你了
One way or another.
如果我失手 计划就完了
And if I don't, none of this works.
你能行的
You can do this.
是吗
Yeah.
我没以前自信了
A week ago, I would have believed you.
莫洛的死 我不怪你
I don't blame you for what happened.
她杀死了你心爱的人 这种痛
She took someone you cared about. That's not something you just
忘不了
let go.
那样感觉好点吗？
Did it make you feel better?
杀死那些杀害你妻子的人
When you killed the men who killed your wife?
人死不能复生
We can't get them back.
听着 要想关闭卫星
Okay, to shut down the satellite,
我们得手动接入中央服务器
we have to manually tap into the central server.
你从排气管道进去 穿上特制的金属外套
You'll enter through the exhaust vent, wearing this under your suit.
然后跳进计算机阵列 我会抓住你
Drop down into the computer array, and I'll catch you,
把你送到主机室 你黑进控制板
then move you along the relay room and you jack into the panel.
我们装成客人分头进去会场
Okay, so we enter the party separately as guests.
伊森指挥行动 简从阔佬那里弄到代码
Ethan quarterbacks while Jane Gets the codes from the billionaire.
我一关风扇 你就往下跳
I switch off the fan, you jump into the computer array,
我抓住你 你把发射机接通
and I catch you, you plug in the transmitter
伊森告诉我代码 我来查找亨德里克斯的位置
then Ethan feeds me the codes which I then use to pinpoint Hendricks' location.
好的 不过有件重要的事 你没说清楚
Okay, but you just breezed over something I think is really important.
那个计算机阵列 我要往哪里跳？
The computer array part, where I just Jump?
- 我会抓住你 - 是的
- And I catch you.  - Yeah.
对啊 这很难理解吗？
I don't. .. Why is that so hard to grasp?
呃...
Well. ..
可那里有25英尺高 而我们用的是磁铁
Why? It's a 25-foot drop. And we're using magnets.
对
Yeah.
之前出了这么多问题 我们的设备是不是...
In light of our recent efforts, the technology's. ..
我们的设备很可靠
The science is sound. All right?
我倒是比较担心热度
I'd be more worried about the heat.
你说什么？什么热度？
And then there's that. What heat?
和普通的电脑一样
Well, it's like any computer, isn't it?
一旦你关掉风扇 机器会变得很热
If you switch off the fan, it's gonna get really hot!
当然
Of course.
一样道理
Relatively, you know.
这我知道 所以我等于是跳进一个...
Of course it will. So I'm jumping into a. ..
烤箱里 对吗？
Uh, an oven, essentially.
没错 烤箱
Yeah. Essentially.
不过 我会抓住你
But, um, I'll catch you.
很好
Great.
(印度  孟买)
欢迎光临
Aapka swagat hai, sir. Welcome, sir.
通讯检查
Comm check.
木星 土星这里听得很清楚
Saturn's got your five-by-five, Jupiter.
我是冥王星
This is Pluto.
我已经到达会场了
I have arrived at the party.
他在那儿
There he is.
把代码弄到手
Get us that code.
金星向目标靠近
Venus moving in on target.
上钩了
Hook's in.
你还真有一套啊
You do make an impression.
为什么叫我冥王星？
Why am I Pluto?
它都不算大行星
It's not even a planet anymore.
嫌它小 你叫银河系啊
Well, I think Uranus is available.
你的嘴真不饶人
It's funny 'cause you said "anus."
我到了
I'm in position.
探测车出发
Sending in the Rover.
他过来了
He's moving to you.
背对他
Give him your back.
别让他觉得太容易
Don't want to make it too easy for him.
你怎么这么啰嗦？
Are you gonna be talking the whole time?
去给所有客人送一杯路易十五特酿香槟
In 20 minutes, I want a glass of Cuve Louis in every guest's hand.
而且要让每个人都带一瓶回家
And make sure all of them have a bottle to take home by the end of the night.
好的
Sure.
感动了吗？
Impressed yet?
我只喝威士忌
I'm more of a bourbon girl.
我叫布瑞吉·纳特
I'm Brij Nath.
欢迎光临寒舍
Welcome to my humble home.
探测车就位
And Rover's in position.
涡轮扇降速
Spinning down the turbine.
他在发邮件
He's e-mailing.
金星 勾引他
Venus. Be Venus.
勾引他
Be Venus.
你老公？
Husband?
男朋友？
Boyfriend?
充其量
More of a
算同事
co-worker.
土星 准备跳
Saturn, take the leap.
好的
Okay.
跳了
Jumping.
要跳了
Jumping now.
现在跳？
Jump now?
是的 确定 跳
Yes. Commit. Jump.
- 跳 - 跳啊
- Jump. - Jump.
- 我会抓住你  - 快跳
- And I catch you.   - Now.
班吉 你确定不会有问题
So, you're sure about this suit, right, Benji?
我确定
Pretty sure.
我有问题
Now you're pretty sure?
快跳
Jump.
好吧
Oh, God. All right.
快跳
Jump.
Jump!
木星 他走了
Jupiter, he's gone.
你跳了吗？
Did you jump?
别告诉我不该跳
Should I not have jumped?
我已经跳了
'Cause I jumped!
待命
Stand by.
我要赌一把
I'm playing a hunch.
别揍我
Don't hit me.
喂？
Hello?
天呐 没想到你还是个多情的主儿
My God, you are a passionate creature.
我想请你看看我收藏的艺术品
I would like to show you my collection of art.
我一直在等你邀请我呢
I was waiting for you to ask.
你得先找到我
Then you have to find me.
没问题
You're on.
我上楼了
I'm heading upstairs.
你得小心点儿
All right, now be careful,
里面可能会变得比较热
because it's probably getting a bit hot.
得赶在亨德里克斯前面接通卫星
We have to get to that satellite before Hendricks does.
看左边 看上面
Look left. Look up.
像你这种多情的姑娘最迷人
I find your capricious passion intriguing.
相信我 他不是你的菜
Let me tell you one thing. He's not your type.
他配不上你 他太冷冰冰了 不像我
Completely not your type. He's completely cold. I'm hot.
我们印度男人热情如火
Like all Indian men, I'm very hot.
八点钟方向
Eight o'clock.
充满激情
Hot! Very hot.
他在你八点钟方向
He's at your eight o'clock.
你越靠近我 就会感觉越来越热
As you move towards me, you're getting hotter.
上去 快上去
Whoa. Ow! Ah! Up, up! Up, up!
喔 太多了
Ah! Too much, too much, too much!
看见你了
I see you.
听说你有世界上最好的私人收藏
I'd heard you have one of the finest private collections in the world.
至少是个私人空间
Well, at the very least, it's private.
土星 你的情况怎么样？
Saturn? How we doing in the relay room?
已经就位
In position.
(接通卫星 准备上传)
我看见卫星了
I see the satellite.
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you, gentlemen?
我看不需要
I don't think so.
我要代码 伙计们
Need those codes, guys.
这些都是切德尔布尔区的真品
All originals from Chhatarpur District.
密教的教徒相信
You know, the Tantrics believe
生殖轮隐藏了我们潜意识里最大的欲望
that the Swadhisthana chakra hides our most subconscious of desires.
嗯
Mmm.
连接这颗卫星 重新启动它的军事参数
Uplink to satellite. Reboot to original military specs.
下载病毒
Download the virus.
怎么回事？
What the hell is that?
What the hell is what?
服务器失控了
It's going haywire!
它在从卫星上下载病毒
It's downloaded a virus from the satellite.
亨德里克斯动手了
Hendricks is killing the server
他想要毁掉服务器
before we can kill the satellite.
他在给卫星重新编程
Hendricks is reprogramming the satellite.
再过五分钟就能用它发射核弹了
He's gonna have launch capability in five minutes!
- 怎么了？ - 没事
- Something wrong?   - No.
简 来不及了 我们要代码
Jane, you gotta move. We need that code.
就剩我们了
Finally we're alone.
金星 行动吧 把他放倒
Venus, now's the time. Kick his ass
拿到代码
and get the code.
只有我们俩 是吗？
We are alone, aren't we?
没有人会打扰我们
No one will interrupt us.
动一下 就要了你的命
Move and I break your neck.
告诉我卫星的接入代码
The override sequence for the relay station.
要想活命 就赶快告诉我
Say it now or never speak again.
快说
The codes.
46 82...
46, 82...
93.
班吉 怎么了？
Benji, what happened?
太晚了 系统崩溃了
The system's crashed! We're too late.
不 他暴露了自己
No, no, no. He's revealed himself.
你能搜索亨德里克斯的位置吗？
Benji, can you pinpoint Hendricks' location?
信号是从6.7英里外的一家电视台发出的
Uh, Hendricks is signaling out of a state-run TV station 6.7 miles from here.
给我坐标
Send me the coordinates.
干得好 勃兰特 快离开那儿
Good work, Brandt. Now get the hell out of there.
让我出去
Back me up!
简 别管纳特了 我们在约定地点碰头
Jane, tie it off with Nath and meet me at the rally point.
做个好梦
Sleep tight
快点 班吉 让我直接上去
Faster, Benji! Just straight through!
等等 停下
Wait! Stop!
直接上去
Take me through!
探测车没反应 你难道就不能再耐心一点吗
It's not responding! A little bit of patience would be appreciated!
还没到顶
I can't reach the top!
风大点 再大点
More fan! More fan!
再大点
More fan!
我没办法 已经最大了
There's nothing I can do! It's maxed out!
(涡轮最大转速 警报)
勃兰特？
Brandt?
下一次 我去勾引阔佬
Next time, I get to seduce the rich guy.
卫星军事参数已经启用
Satellite weaponized and online.
现在上传新的认证密码
Upload the new authentication codes.
防止中央司令部进入系统
Lock Russian Central Command out of the system.
隔离潜水艇
Isolate the sub.
我们将只发射一枚导弹 作为对克里姆林宫爆炸案的反击
We'll fire just one missile, an apparent retaliation for the Kremlin.
这足够点燃导火线了
That should start the ball rolling.
我在 伊森
I'm here, Ethan.
启动发射程序要多久？
How long until Hendricks can launch a missile?
(卫星重新定位)
用不了30秒钟
Less than 30 seconds!
找条近路
We need another route.
左转 走右边的小路
Turn left up ahead, take the alley on the right.
上传完成
We have uplink.
(发射程序启动)
伊森 亨德里克斯启动发射程序了
Ethan, Hendricks has started the launch sequence.
导弹多久会发射？
How much time until missiles are flying?
三分钟
Three minutes!
到电视台要三分半钟
We're three and a half minutes out.
一定能赶上
We can make it.
（太平洋中部 麦哲伦海台）
艇长...
Captain...
快去跟中央司令部确认发射命令
Connect to Central Command for launch verification.
是 艇长
Right away.
立即开始执行"铁拳行动"
Proceed with Operation "Iron Fist".
发射命令已经得到确认
Command to Launch is confirmed.
现在起终止一切联系
Cease all further communication.
通话完毕
Over and out.
往左转
Next left.
开始
Proceed.
伊森 来不及了
Ethan? We're too late.
导弹上天了
The missile's in the air.
一定能终止弹头爆炸
There has to be a way to abort the warhead.
发射装置上应该有终止按钮
If there is one, it'll be on the launch device.
我们去拿箱子
We're gonna get that case.
愿地球能永远和平
May there be peace on Earth.
毁掉主机
Disable the relay.
抓住维斯特伦 快进去
Get Wistrom! Inside, inside!
维斯特伦毁了主机
Wistrom destroyed the relay.
伊森去追亨德里克斯和箱子了
Ethan went after Hendricks and the case, but...
就算拿到箱子 也没法破译终止密码
Doesn't matter if he has the case. We can't transmit the abort codes.
能修好吗？
Can you fix it?
可以 不过没电源也是白搭
Uh, yeah. .. It's gonna be pointless if we don't have any power.
维斯特伦
Wistrom!
- 简  - 我没事
- Jane!   - I'm okay.
不 你受伤了 她中弹了
No, you are not okay. She's hit.
你待在这儿 掩护班吉
You stay here and cover Benji.
班吉 你把线路重新恢复 我去弄电源
Benji, get this thing rewired and back online. I'll get the power on.
我们能行
We can do this.
快点 把箱子给我
I'm taking that briefcase!
不 不
No! No!
他怎么还不回来
He's been gone too long.
见鬼 听着
Damn it! Listen.
等电源来了 把驱动器装进这个槽里 懂吗？
When the power comes on, these two drives go into this bay, okay?
任务完成了
Mission accomplished!
(任务终止)
别碰他
Don't touch him!
他是我的
This one is mine.
这么说 我们不是敌人
So, we are not enemies.
是你让那个军火商联系我的
The phone call from that arms dealer in Dubai.
你希望我找到你
You wanted me to find you.
真是让人难以置信
How else to believe this?
去医院吗？
Hospital?
其他方面消息 八星期了 这场争论还在继续
And in other news, eight weeks later, the debate continues.
许多目击者坚持称 他们当时看到的物体是某种飞行器
Eyewitnesses remain adamant that the object was some sort of aircraft,
但是国防部官员声称 那只是一颗体积比较大的陨石
but officials with the Department of Defense insist it was simply a meteor
所以会在白天观测到
large enough to be visible during daylight.
你当时真的这么做了
You actually said that.
大喊一声
Out loud.
"任务完成了"
"Mission accomplished."
没错
I said it.
天呐 你真是没创意
You're still corny, Ethan.
那坏蛋准是被你活活气死的
I can't imagine the look on that guy's face.
- 嗨  - 就是他们
- Hey. - This must be them.
卢瑟·斯迪克尔 他们是 简 班吉 勃兰特
Luther Stickell, the firm of Carter, Dunn and Brandt.
我整个周末都在旧金山湾里帮你们收拾残局
I blew an entire weekend on the bottom of the San Francisco Bay
你们本事够大的
no thanks to you clowns.
我来买单
No, man, you know I got this.
我知道 坎大哈见
I know. I'll see you in Kandahar.
谢谢你们能来
Thanks for meeting me.
我听说你撞坏的那辆车
So, I hear the insurance company's refusing
保险公司不肯赔
to pay the claim on that car you crashed, Ethan.
他们说 故意让车从百米高空垂直坠下 不属于赔付范围
Something about intentional 100-meter vertical drops not being covered.
真是奸商啊
Go figure.
腿怎么样?
How's the leg?
还能用
Still working.
你呢？
You?
好多了
Healing.
我的手好了
I'm fine, by the way.
不过我一直睡眠不太好
I mean, I'm not actually sleeping, per se.
常常半夜里出冷汗
You know. Cold sweats. Middle of the night.
这儿的人都这么开心 我真是羡慕
All these people are just happy and smiling
他们完全不知道
and they are completely oblivious to the fact
自己差一点就瞬间蒸发了
that they were almost vaporized.
而且要不是因为...
And if it hadn't been for. ..
狗屎运？
Dumb luck?
对吗？
Was it?
你们想 我们没准备 没情报
I mean, look, we were unprepared, in the dark.
也没支援
Disavowed.
那时候唯一运转正常的...
And the only thing that functioned properly on that mission
就只有这个团队
was this team.
我不知道是怎么撑过来的
I don't know how we ended up together,
但是成功了
but I'm glad we did.
你们自己决定
Your missions.
是不是参加
Choose to accept them.
嗯 我参加
Hey, look, I'm in.
应该没什么任务比上次
Seriously. It's not as if any mission
更危险 更困难吧
is gonna be rougher than the last one, is it?
我是说 只是...
I mean, that's just...
别又是炸弹 是吗？
Bomb. .. Is it?
谢谢你 伊森
Thanks, Ethan.
谢谢你
Thank you.
亨特特工
Agent Hunt.
卡特特工
Agent Carter.
勃兰特
Brandt.
我没有拿那个电话 伊森
I'm not picking up that phone, Ethan,
我觉得你可能不希望我参加
because I don't think you want me in the field.
我知道你妻子死了
I know your wife is dead.
我当时就在那里
I was there in Croatia.
我去那里执行一个任务
I was there for one reason.
就一个
One.
可是 我失败了
And I failed.
我的任务是保护她
It was my job to protect her.
你怎么知道她死了？
How do you know she's dead?
找到尸体了
There was a body.
你看见了？
Did you see it?
你杀了那些人
You killed those Serbians.
为了救她回来
I had to get her back.
你被送进监狱
You were sent to Rankow Prison.
这是我自愿做出的牺牲
That was a sacrifice I was willing to make.
IMF怀疑监狱里有亨德里克斯的人
IMF suspected Hendricks had people in Rankow.
杀手的死为你坐牢提供了理由
And six dead Serbians was the ideal cover.
也算为民除害吧
Waste not, want not.
部长从没告诉我
The Secretary never told me.
我接受兰卡监狱的任务只有一个条件:
I accepted the Rankow Prison mission on one condition:
不能有人知道她还活着
That no one could know she was still alive.
可你告诉我了
But you're telling me.
你什么时候发现我去过那里？
When did you find out that I was in Croatia?
从印度回来我查了档案
I pulled your file after India.
懂了
Right.
你伪造了你妻子的死
So you had to fake your wife's death.
和我在一起 她永远不会安全
As long as we were together, she could never be safe.
勃兰特 保护她不是你的任务
It wasn't your job to protect her, Brandt.
是我的
It's mine.
那好
Okay.
就这样
So we're good.
We're good.
快来啊
Come on!
晚上好 亨特先生
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
36小时前 我们的军方通讯网络遭到破坏
36 hours ago, there was a breach in our military's communication network.
现在一个叫辛迪加的新兴恐怖组织
Now, an emerging terror organization known as The Syndicate
控制了我们整个无人舰队 他们的目的还不清楚
has control of our entire drone fleet. Their targets: Unknown.
你将决定是否接受这个任务...
Your mission, should you choose to accept it...